Guide to the Richard Pollay Acme Advertising Collection, 1850s-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Series 4: Office and School Supplies, 1889-2000 and undated
  - 100-04-078. Unknown (No company name). Acme Hospitals Equipment letter opener, undated (Box 8)
    End of letter opener has colored enamel logo of creating company. Metal beds, Electrical conduit. Good condition.
  - 100-04-079. Acme Photo Company letter opener, undated (Box 8)
    Letter opener is rusting, company information is raised on handle. Fair condition.
  - 100-04-080. Acme pens, undated (Box 8)
    3 pens, blue plastic bodies, with white stripes. White erasers attached. Come in original package. Card inside: Imported by Acme Mount Forest, ONT Some ink has leaked in packaging. Fair condition.
  - 100-04-081. Acme Rents clip board, undated (Box 8)
    Acme Rents almost everything. Wooden backing. Metal clip screwed into wood. Rust. Water stains. Scratched. Fair condition.
  - 100-04-082. Acme Tape Measure, undated (Box 8)
    Wooden tape measure folds out in sections. Pencil marks. Made in USA. Signs of wear but in good condition. Metal tipped.
  - 100-04-083. Acme Laundry Co. Ruler, undated (Box 8)
    Patronize your neighborhood laundry. --Acme Red Cap. Tops for all laundry services. White coated metal ruler. Scratched. Metric and imperial measurement. Made in USA. Good condition.
  - 100-04-084. Acme National Refrigeration. Ruler, undated (Box 8)
    Efficiency refrigeration. Compact Kitchens. --Acme where inches count. White coated metal ruler. Scratched. Metric and imperial measurement. Made in USA. Good condition.
  - 100-04-085. Acme Display Fixture Co. Ruler, undated (Box 8)
    Garment hangers, mannequins, garment racks, plastic shoulder covers, salesman's supplies. Green coated metal ruler. Metric and imperial measurement. Made in USA. Good condition.
  - 100-04-086. Acme Telephone Answering Service. Ruler, undated (Box 8)
    We do more than just answer your phone. We watch your business for you. Worchester's oldest answering service Green coated metal ruler. Scratched. Made in USA. Metric and imperial measurement. Rust. Fair condition.
  - 100-04-087. Acme Casket Company. Ruler, undated (Box 8)
    Manufacturing caskets of distinction. Our Rule--Quality is our first consideration Wooden varnished ruler. Inches and picas. Good condition.
  - 100-04-088. Acme. Ruler, undated (Box 8)
    Acme wooden varnished ruler. Imperial and metric measurements. Also French used. Made in Canada. Good condition.
  - 100-04-089. Acme Industrial Company. Ruler, undated (Box 8)
    Standardized Drill Jig Bushings Small slim steel ruler, angled at one end. Good condition.
  - 100-04-090. Acme Markets. Ruler, undated (Box 8)
    More and More Shoppers are Saying Meet Me at the Acme White coated metal ruler. Scratched. Imperial measurement only. Made in USA. Good condition.
  - 100-04-091. Acme Card System Company. Signals, undated (Box 8)
    Box contains 5 boxes or original Colored card signals used by Acme Card System. Signals are color coated metal. Original packaging. Good condition.
  - 100-04-092. Acme United Limited. Fold back clips, undated (Box 8)
    Box of Acme metal fold back clips. Original box. Good condition.
  - 100-04-093. Acme Boat Company. Ruler, 1965 (Box 8)
    Your one stop shop for all your marine needs Ruler is in inches only. Darkened wood. Smells of grease? Fair condition.
  - 100-04-094. Acme Pencil Company. Pencil, undated (Box 8)
    A substitute for brush and ink. Will mark on any surface Original box contains 12 unused (17 cm) blue marking pencils. Good condition. Box is deteriorating.
  - 100-04-095. Acme Tag Company. Pencil and paper clip holder, 1921 (Box 8)
    Brass. Lid opens up and has 1921 calendar under it. Rust. Discolored. Fair condition.
  - 100-04-096. Acme Window Coverings. Tape measure, undated (Box 8)
    Steel tape measure. Blue lettering. Company information on lighter. Original plastic box: Zippo Lifetime guarantee Excellent Condition.
  - 100-04-097. UBC, Acme Academy Core binder, 1990s (Box 8)
    One gray, 3-ring binder with Acme Academy, UBC MBA Core, University of British Columbia, Faculty of Commerce and Business Administration on cover. UBC logo in one corner. Excellent condition.
  - 100-04-098. Acme Printing Ink Company. Pocket tape measure, undated (Box 7)
    Pocket tape measure in the form of a Zippo lighter. On the face of the lighter is the logo of the Acme Printing Ink Company, Chicago. Pull-out tape measure has Zippo printed on the tape and on bottom of the item. Scratches on item.
  - 100-04-099. Acme Ruler and Advertising Company. Limited display holder, undated (Box 47A)
    One gray wooden display box for Acme school and office rulers. Bos has compartments for different sized rulers. Back of box has paper label on the contents of display and how to re-order Box is empty. Paper label is torn at the corners, pain has chipped off in certain areas, some cracks on the wooden surface, several stains on the side. Text on paper label includes: Acme Ruler and Advertising Company, Limited, manufacturers of Acme Wood Specialities.
  - 100-04-100. Intersave West Buying and Merchandising Services. Acme cassette tape, undated (Box 8)
    One Acme C-90 (MS1000) cassette tape in its original plastic shrink-wrap. Label stuck on plastic wrap reads: Imported by Intersave West Buying and Merchandising Services Calgary. Made in China Text in English and French. Item in good condition.
  - 100-04-101. Intersave West Buying and Merchandising Services. Acme cassette tape, undated (Box 8)
    One Acme C-90 (MS800) cassette tape with case. Made in China. Item in good condition.
  - 100-04-102. Acme cassette tape, undated (Box 7)
    One Acme C-60 cassette tape with case. Does not seem to have been used. Item in good condition.
  - 100-04-103. Acme VHS tape, undated (Box 8)
    One Acme E-180 VHS video tape in its original plastic shrink-wrap. Product information on the back of the tape is in English, French and German. Item in good condition.
  - 100-04-104. Acme Furnace Fitting Company. Clipboard, 1955 (Box 8)
    One metal clipboard with adjustable slide calendar (1955-1959). Green felt backing. Instructions on using and setting the calendar on the board itself. Minor scratches.
  - 100-04-105. Acme Industries, Inc. Pencil, undated (Box 8)
    One mechanical pencil, marble-like pale yellow finish. Silver tip. Durolite on shirtclip. Text on pencil: Acme Industries, Inc. Jackson, Michigan, Manufacturing of quality air conditioning and refrigeration equipment since 1919 Logo on other end. Temp and pressure table also printed on pen. Pen does not work.
  - 100-04-106. Loncraine Broxton and Partners Limited. A Dress book, 1985 (Box 8)
    One fancy address book called A Dress Book Cover is made to look like a suit complete with striped shirt, vest with gold chain, necktie coat with a pink flower on the lapel and handkerchief with Acme embroidered on it. Several handwritten entries in address book. Label of Loncraine Broxton and Partners Limited of Stanford, England is in the inside cover. Item in good condition.
  - [Image only] 100-04-107. Acme School of Drawing. Notebook, undated (Box 8)
    Brown colored notebook from Acme School of Drawing; front and back covers show beautiful drawing and text Drawing taught the Acme way Framed in glass.
  - 100-04-108. Acme Printing Ink, Company. Pencil, 1920s (Box 8)
    White and black celluloid (?) pencil, text on pencil reads Acme Printing Ink Company Chicago, followed by address and phone: Haymarket 1-0676. Chicago 7 Pencil has some discoloration. Made in USA, Redipen In good condition.
  - 100-04-110. Acme Feed, Seed and Fertilizer Company. Oversized ruler, undated (Box 49C)
    One wooden ruler with Acme Feed, Seed and Fertilizer Company-101 Broadway-Prodding for your business painted on one side and If you want to step-up your yields, lean on us! on the reverse side. On one end of the ruler is No. V-463 by SAMCO Ruler has a hole on one side, so it can hang from a hook or nail. Item in good condition.
  - 100-04-111. Acme Pencil Company. Pencil, undated (Box 8)
    Four black marking pencils, nos. 2 and 4. Pink paper wrappers with text: Made in all colors, a substitute for the brush for marking boxes, barrels, packages,etc. Will not rub or wash off, Sold under a guarantee. The hardest and best oil crayon made. Manufactured by The Acme Pencil Company, Chester, Penn., USA
  - [Image only] 100-04-112. Acme Brick paperweight, undated (Box 8)
    One miniature brick paperweight with Acme Brick etched on top. Paperweight has a fake gold finish with a round gold spot at the centre. On spots where the gold paint is worn out, the actual brick color shows underneath the paint. Worn out green felt backing on the bottom. See also 100-04-27 for a similar Acme Brick paperweight.
  - 100-04-113. Acme spelling tablet, undated (Box 8)
    One slim spelling tablet from the Acme School Series, with cardboard cover and lined, numbered pages. Some pages already torn out. Cover is stained; pages are yellow with age but free from any writing.
  - 100-04-114. Acme Associates, Inc. Pencil, undated (Box 8)
    One gray colored lead pencil; stencilled on the body is Acme Associates, Inc. Los Angeles, California, Logan 3304
  - 100-04-116. Acme Electric. Pencil, undated (Box 7)
    Metal and plastic mechanical pencil. Red lettering on beige background. Acme Electric--Transformers Neon Engineering and Supply, Inc. Wichita.
  - [Image only] 100-04-117. Acme Steel Credit Union. Tape measure, undated (Box 7)
    Metal mini tape measure. Red lettering on white background. Acme Steel Credit Union--849-3113 Imperial units.
  - [Image only] 100-04-118. Acme Fruit Exchange. Paperweight, 1930s/1940s (Box 7)
    Glass paperweight. Black lettering on white background. The Best From the West--Acme Wenatchee Valley Fruit Exchange--Apples and Pears Car Lots Only--Seattle--Dryden--White Bluffs--Hanford--Main Office Cashmere, Wash Historical Note: White Bluffs and Hanford, WA no longer exist. They were bulldozed in 1943 as part of the Manhattan Project. The sites of the towns are now within the bounds of the Department of Energy's Hanford Site, the world's largest nuclear waste site.
  - [Image only] 100-04-119. Acme Plating Company. Letter opener, undated (Box 7)
    Metal blade with black leather sheath and handle. Silver lettering. The Acme Plating Company--1563 East 21st Street--Cherry 1-0337--Cleveland 14, Ohio
  - 100-04-121. Acme Gear Company. Paper Organizer/Desk item, undated (Box 7)
    Green paper organizer/desk item. Two slots for holding papers. Yellow text on side reads: Seasons Greetings--Acme Gear Company, Milwaukee.
  - [Image only] 100-04-122. Acme Ice Company. Ruler, undated (Box 7)
    Flexible thin metal ruler. Black lettering on beige background. Acme Ice Company--For Delivery Call Fairfax 8838--Ice--Solid or Crushed--Ice Cold Beer--Iced Soft Drinks
  - 100-04-123. Acme Manufacturing Company. Ruler, undated (Box 7)
    Dark wood ruler. Gold lettering. Acme Manufacturing Company--Makers of Genuine Tennessee Red Cedar Chests--World Fame--Acme Chests Excel Them All
  - 100-04-124. Acme Cleveland Corporation. Paperweight, 1976 (Box 7)
    Clear plastic paperweight with token set inside. Raised lettering on token. Acme Cleveland Corporation Centennial 1976-1976--United States of America Bicentennial 1776-1976
  - 100-04-125. Acme Advertising Associates. Penknife and letter opener, undated (Box 7)
    2 metal blades. White handle. Black lettering. Compliments of Acme Advertising Associates, Inc.
  - 100-04-126. Acme Industries Inc. Slide rule, undated (Box 7)
    White slide rule with brown leather sheath. Blue and black lettering on rule. Acme Industries Inc. Jackson, Michigan
  - 100-04-127. Acme Ruler Company, Ltd. Titanium scissors, 1990s-2000s (Box 7)
    Blue and red handle. Metal blades. Black lettering on blades. Acme Titanium--#13739
  - 100-04-128. Acme Bearing Service Company. Ruler, undated (Box 7)
    Metal ruler with leather sheath. Gold lettering on brown sheath. Acme Bearing Service Company Black lettering on silver ruler. Acme Bearing Service--Fafnir Ball Bearings--Bearing Specialists. Good condition.
  - 100-04-129. Acme Brick Company. Ruler, 1992 (Box 7)
    Material is brass. Black lettering. Acme Brick Company--Centennial Celebration 1891-1991 Reverse has monthly calendar for 1992.
  - 100-04-130. Acme Auto Parts. Ruler, 1969 (Box 7)
    Thin metal ruler. Brown lettering on yellow background. Acme Auto Parts--Harrisburg, Penn. Small monthly calendars fro July 1969--October 1970. Crease in metal.
  - 100-04-131. Acme novelty rubber stamp, 1990s-2000s (Box 7)
    Rubber stamp on wood block. Design is of a tray of bottles. Acme Rubber Cement As new condition.
  - 100-04-132. Acme rubber stamp, undated (Box 7)
    Wood handle and wood base with rubber stamp. Stylized Acme No other identifying information.
  - 100-04-133. Acme Sewer Cleaning Company. Pencil, undated (Box 7)
    Mechanical pencil. Tortoise shell colors. Black text reads: Acme Sewer Cleaning Company--Cherry 3344--Clogged Pipe and Sewer Specialists--Flooded Basements Pumped. See similar item 100-04-109.
  - 100-04-134. Acme Foundry and Machine Company. Dispensing container, 1942 (Box 7)
    Wood box whose lid opens and closes automatically when the box is turned upside down. Opens to reveal two compartments meant to contain cigarettes. In cardboard case. Small label reads: The Acme Foundry and Machine Company, Coffeyville, Kansas. Stamped inside: Bottoms Up--Patent No. 2,316,979
  - 100-04-135. Acme Plate Corp. Corporate seal, 1957 (Box 7)
    Metal painted black. Impression reads Acme Plate Corp. Corporate Seal 1957 New York Working condition.
  - 100-04-136. Acme Guano Co. Pencil, undated (Box 7)
    Regular wood pencil. Black and red lettering on yellow background. The Acme Guano Company--Fertilizer Manufacturers--Acme Quality in Every Bag--Baltimore, MD Good condition.
  - 100-04-137. Acme Motor Truck Company. Pencil, undated (Box 7)
    Regular wood pencil. Red lettering on pink background. Acme Motor Truck Company--Worm Driven Motor Trucks--Seven Sizes--Cadillac,--Mich Metal around eraser is rusted and broken.
  - 100-04-138. Acme Supply Company. Ruler, undated (Box 7)
    Wood ruler. Black text. Acme Supply Company. A Good Rule--Call Acme--Falcon--11 South St. Auburn--4-7951--Stock No. 28 Pen marks.
- Series 5: Domestic Hardware, 1910-1994 and undated
  - 100-05-001. J. Hudson and Company. (Whistles) Ltd. Acme Survival Whistle, 1990s (Box 9)
    Survival whistle No. 649, made of plastic, bright orange color; shows logo Acme Whistles all over the world. Text in English, French and German. In mint condition. Whistle satisfies safety regulations and approved for use in life craft, rescue boats. Made in China.
  - 100-05-002. Tiderider Inc. Acme Thunderer whistles, undated (Box 9)
    A dozen silver whistles, each wrapped in cellophane, in original box. Acme logo on lid of box; text includes Whistle Specialties Guaranteed Sound. One side of box reads: Every Acme is carefully tested and sounded before leaving the factory and is, therefore, returnable if faulty when purchased. Made in England, however, label on left side of box reads: Tiderider Inc. Balwin, N.Y.
  - 100-05-003. Lavelle Rubber Company. Faucet washers tin, undated (Box 9)
    One yellow colored tin of Acme beveled faucet washers; empty; stamped on front of tin is 1/2, 2 1/2. Other text includes product information. Lid is tightly shut; scratches and stains on tin; handwriting on lid.
  - 100-05-004. Acme measuring tape, undated (Box 9)
    One metal retractable measuring tape; tape of 16 ft.; still in its original packaging. Price sticker reads $21.95. Text in English and French. Imported from Japan.
  - 100-05-005. Acme Ruler Company. Measuring tape, undated (Box 9)
    One metal retractable measuring tape with a short chain and hook; tape of 3 ft.; still in its original packaging. Price sticker reads $3.95. Text in English and French. Imported from Taiwan.
  - 100-05-006. Acme Coal and Lime Company. Wall thermometer, undated (Box 9)
    One cream colored metal wall thermometer from Acme Coal and Lime Company. Glass is broken; red dye stain at the back. Metal frame is scratched and worn out. Phone Number on the bottom of the thermometer reads: C=8151.
  - 100-05-007. Acme Industrial Company. Drill bushing sample comparison kit, undated (Box 9)
    One kit used to compare 5 types of Acme-made metal bushings against 5 bushings from other manufacturers. Paper insert tucked in inside cover. Vinyl covered box with gold locks. Text on lid: Acme Industrial Company, Chicago 7, Ill. Scratches and stains on bottom of box.
  - 100-05-008. Acme Soap Company. Glass shine, undated (Box 9)
    One empty, plastic bottle of glass shine. Paper label on bottle reads: Acme Soap Company, Quality detergents since 1952. Includes description of product and directions for use.
  - 100-05-009. Acme Brick key tag, undated (Box 9)
    Acme Brick metal key tag, with card registration form, in original plastic packaging. Key tag meant to be attached to set of keys and, if lost, can be mailed to Acme Brick. Inscription on key tag reads: Acme Brick Since 1891.
  - 100-05-010. Acme Auto Supply, Inc. Paper bag, undated (Box 9)
    One large brown paper bag with printed label: More than auto parts. Auto people. Acme. Acme Auto Supply, Inc.
  - 100-05-011. Acme Auto Supply, Inc. Paper bag, undated (No image available) (Box 9)
    One small brown paper bag with printed label: More than auto parts. Auto people. Acme. Acme Auto Supply, Inc.
  - 100-05-012. Acme Quality Products, Inc. Radial tire gauge, undated (Box 9)
    One metal radial tire gauge in its original store packaging. A515 BL. --Acme inscribed on gauge holder. Brass construction. Item in excellent condition.
  - 100-05-013. Do-Ray Lamp Company, Canada, Ltd. Bicycle tire gauge, undated (Box 9)
    One bicycle tire gauge, A525 BL, in its original store packaging. Text in English and French. Text includes: Acme Tire Hardware. Company information reads: Do-Ray Lamp Company. Canada Ltd. And Acme Tire Hardware.
  - 100-05-014. Acme Quality Products, Inc. Valve caps, undated (Box 9)
    One set of four dome type valve caps for cars and bicycles; comes in its original store packaging. Acme A 310 BL.
  - 100-05-015. Acme Plumbing and Heating Supplies. Tape measure, undated (Box 9)
    One round sized tape measure with red pull out fabric tape. On both sides of the tape is the label for Acme Plumbing and Heating Supplies, Manufactures and Wholesalers, Pipe, Valves, Fittings. At the center of label is Sam D'Amico Jr. Phone HO 5-8000. Tape is made in Germany.
  - 100-05-016. Acme Air App. Co., Inc. Valve cores, undated (Box 9)
    One tin of Acme valve cores, 6 pcs.; item has a lid that slides out. Text on lid includes; Acme for accuracy. Text on the sides of the tin read: Over a quarter century of progress and Acme Air App. Co., Inc. Hackensack, N. J. A bit tarnished at the bottom of tin. Comes with receipt of purchase addressed to Richard Pollay for $3.00.
  - 100-05-017. Schwartz Manufacturing Company. Casters, undated (Box 9)
    One boxed set of four Acme ball bearing casters and 18 screws. Box reads: The best and most popular caster in the world,For industrial and domestic use A. B. C. casters, and Smooth running positive action. Box is heavily stained, inside and out.
  - 100-05-018. Acmeline Manufacturing Company. Insect sprayer, undated (Box 9)
    One Acme metal insect sprayer can with a wooden handle. Black and faded gold colors. Tube reads: Acme registered quality sprayer. Canister welded to the tube displays Acme on its front. At the bottom of the tube is a little hole and the words Oil here. Scratches, some rust on item.
  - 100-05-019. Acmeline Manufacturing Company. Insect sprayer, undated (Box 9)
    One metal sprayer with a wooden handle but missing its canister. Orange and blue colors on the tube that reads: Acme sprayers and dusters, built to last, Gold seal Acme quality.
  - 100-05-020. Acme-lite Manufacturing Company. Extension cord, undated (Box 9)
    One 3-way photo-extension cord, 15 feet in length. Label on Green and white, tube package provides illustration, directions for use and the trademark logo: Acme-lite your way to better pictures, makers of fine photographic lighting equipment. SAFE in bold letters on one side of tube. Lid of tube is town. Several tears on label.
  - 100-05-021. Acme clothes line reel, undated (Box 9)
    One metal retractable clothes line reel with red wooden handle. For use indoors. Inscribed on side is Acme MGMC. Some rust on metal holder.
  - 100-05-022. Acme Brick Company. Measuring tape, undated (Box 9)
    One round metal measuring tape; Face of tape reads: Acme Brick Company, Established 1891 in faded red letters; back reads: No. 7566 Patented 1964280. Printed on the metal retractable tape is: Stanley Patented.
  - 100-05-023. AcmeTrack Limited. Door wrench, undated (Box 9)
    One bi-folding door adjustment ratchet wrench in its original packaging. Wrench has Acme logo on the handle. Store card is in English and French. Reverse side of card shows illustrations and directions on use. Price sticker reads: Dunbar's Lumber Supply $4.55. Plastic packaging is dusty and torn in several places.
  - 100-05-024. Acme Air Appliance Company, Inc. Glass fuses, undated (Box 9)
    Each orange and blue tin holds 4 pcs of glass fuses. Cover reads: SFE-30 Acme for Accuracy. Glass Fuses. In one corner is the command Press here to open the lid. Bottom of lid lists the other products of Acme Air Appliance.
  - 100-05-025. Acme oil stone, undated (Box 9)
    One dark oil stone in its own wood storage case. Label on face of lid reads: Acme Combination oil-stone for carpenters and general mechanics tools. Coarse side for fast cutting, fine side gives keen edge. Use thin oil, Keeps stone clean. Box is chipped in the corners, scratches on box and tears on the paper label.
  - 100-05-026. Acme Steel Company. Weight calculator, undated (Box 9)
    One stainless steel Acme superstrip weight calculator for weights and sizes. The strip that pulls out marks the Feet and Width. The holder marks the Lbs. on one end and Gauge on the other end. On the back of the ruler are the directions for use; one corner reads Cold rolled Colorstrip, the other reads: Hot rolled Electro Galv.
  - 100-05-027. Acme Extension speaker, 1968 (Box 9)
    One tubular extension speaker, Model TS-30, for any size TR-radios. Tube is covered with vinyl material and speaker rests on a stand with Made in Japan on it. Comes in its original box with paper label on the side.
  - 100-05-028. Acmetrack Limited. Sliding door pull, undated (Box 9)
    Two finger door pulls in its original packaging; text in English and French. Front of card reads: Acme Sliding Door Hardware. Finger Door Pull. Reverse of card provides directions and illustrations for use. Price sticker reads Lumber land $1.29. In excellent condition.
  - 100-05-029. Acme Quality Paints. Tack rag, undated (Box 9)
    One tack rags for cars, in its original plastic package. Front side of the package reads: Acme Automotive Finishes Tack rag 18x36. Price sticker reads: $0.65.
  - 100-05-030. Acme padlock, undated (Box 9)
    One brass Acme padlock, very rusty, and locked with no accompanying key. Both sides of lock display the Acme logo against a faded red background.
  - 100-05-031. Trimm vintage radio headphones, 1930s (Box 9)
    One pair of Trimm radio headphones with black bakelite ear caps, metal headband, and cloth cords. Embossed on ear caps is: Acme Deluxe. Trimm, Chicago, USA.
  - 100-05-032. Acme Club. Bottle opener and spoon, undated (Box 9)